Tyler J. Roberts

(262) 388-4050 | tjroberts314@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/tyleroberts | https://github.com/tyler314

Summary

Software engineer with 6+ years experience in development and design. My most recent work has been well-balanced between building back-end systems, and front-end web applications. I'm seeking a role where I can leverage the experience I have to be a contributing member to a passionate team, that also requires me to learn new skill sets to succeed.

Experience

Software Engineer & Project Manager

 ${\bf Copper\,+\,Honey\,\,Salon\,\cdot\,Freelance}$

Feb 2023 — Present · Remote

- https://www.copperandhoneysalon.com
- I work as the sole Software Engineer on a small business' website. I work directly with the owners to understand their needs, and design software solutions to meet them.
- Created timelines and delivery checkpoints, conducted demos for the owners, and managed all parties involved including an independent UX Designer.
- Leveraged AWS tools such as Cloudfront and AWS Amplify for caching and simple CI/CD, respectively.
- Designed solution for the client so they can easily add and remove employees from the site, seamlessly working across all screen sizes.
- Delivered fully functional website from scratch, and continuing to add new features for the clients.
- Tools & Technologies: AWS, Javascript, React.js, Material UI.

Software Engineer

Warner Bros. Discovery · Contract

 $Mar 2023 - Dec 2023 \cdot Remote$

- I worked on the Customer Data Ingestion Team within MAX streaming. Team owns the back-end system microservices that sends HTTP requests from MAX app users. The system consumes user data, enriches, and stores it to be used by downstream users.
- Within my first month I became a key team contributor by quickly becoming apart of on-call rotations, contributing to code reviews, and pushing code to assist in the MAX launch in May.
- Led efforts of designing novel integration tests, and setting up new Grafana monitoring + alerts for the team's new MAX services, requiring research, cross-team collaboration and team sign-offs.
- I became the lead engineer tasked with onboarding a new service from a re-org. Required collaboration with three away teams, to understand it and get the service running before my contract's end.
- General Operational Excellence. Served on-call shifts, performed load tests before big launches, contributed to documentation for the new services we were building.
- Tools & Technologies: AWS, Typescript, Node.js, Express.js, Kafka, Grafana, Kubernetes + Docker.

Software Engineer

Amazon.com · Full-Time

 $Dec 2019 - Jan 2023 \cdot Seattle, WA$

- I worked on the Alexa Content Management System (ACMS) used by content creators to author Alexa responses. As well as the Adaptive Response Management System (ARMS), a real time service responsible for filtering and selecting content to be served to our customers, with a tps of over 10k and a maximum latency of 200 ms.
- Lead engineer in delivering adapted responses for Smart Home requests. Such features include sharing insights to customers who make a bad request, listing device capabilities of the requested device, and having Alexa say "Good Morning / Night" when a smart light is turned on or off, depending on time of day.
- Developed a Brief / Verbose Mode for ACMS. This allowed the authoring of responses targeted to customers who have their Alexa devices' brief mode setting turned on, as well as to those who have it turned off. Developed the setting on the front-end, worked with internal 3P teams to read the brief mode setting from Alexa customers and ingested it into ARMS, and developed filtering logic to serve the correct responses based on individual requests.
- Migrated all of Alexa personality content from the old content management system, to ACMS/ARMS. This was a three month endeavor that required the development of bulk migration scripts, working closely with a select few engineers, PMs, and content creators across all supported locales. Had daily standups just for this project.
- Led our org in hiring software development engineers by conducting over 50 interviews in Q1 2022. This allowed our org to get a higher head count for engineers we were allowed to hire. I received our orgs quarterly award for this effort.
- Social chair for my org, responsible for organizing quarterly events to get teammates socializing outside of work. I felt this was especially important during the post-pandemic world where many teammates don't see each other as often due to remote work.
- Tools & Technologies: AWS, Kotlin, Javascript, React.js, CI/CD Code Pipelines, Git.

Software Engineer

Cockroach Labs · Full-Time

 $May 2019 - Sep 2019 \cdot New York, NY$

Cockroach Labs

- Apart of the Bulk I/O team, which is responsible for bulk operations in the database, including backup and restore, and schema changes in the database.
- Fixed issue where the dump operation would include interleaved table statements inside of create table statements, causing dependency issues upon a restore.
- Designed features for the backup & restore process to include additional metadata about the cluster. Required a redesign of how the process worked, and reduced manual steps by the user.
- Tools & Technologies: Golang, SQL, Git/Github.

Software Engineer

Dataminr · Full-Time

Sep 2018 - Feb 2019 · New York, NY

- Work on developing the tools used to search and filter through the Twitter pipeline and other media sources.
- JVM code base comprised of Scala and Java. Applications ran on AWS, and much of the day to day work involved use with the AWS tech stack. Kinesis was used for processing the large data sources, where S3 was used to store the raw data.
- Migrated Pastebin data source from Kinesis to Kafka. Involved dependencies between several teams, and required collaboration amongst them.
- Tools & Technologies: Scala, Java, Maven, Docker, AWS, Google Guice, Git/Gitlab, IntelliJ, MacOS.

Software Engineer

IBM Corporation · Full-Time

Jul 2017 - Aug 2019 · Yorktown Heights, NY

- Developed Python application on another team that moved their locally stored data and user accounts to Bluemix, IBM's cloud platform as a service.
- Designed and engineered a web application from the ground up using HTML, CSS, Angular, and Bootstrap. Responsible for the front-end, including page navigation using an MVC design pattern.
- Used Docker to rigorously test the deployment of the web application onto the servers.
- Tools & Technologies: Python, Docker, HTML, Angular, Javascript, PyCharm, MacOS.

Education

B.S. Computer Engineering, Computer Science, & Mathematics with Physics Certificate (minor). University of Wisconsin - Madison, May 2017